Scott Vidler

Mobile: 0402 420 401 Email: scottyv6@gmail.com

LinkedIn: GitHub:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-vidler-77a057218/ https://github.com/scottyv6

I am a full stack developer having recently completed a six month web development/coding Boot Camp through the University of Western Australia. My skills include HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, Express.js, SQL, Sequelize, MongoDB and GraphQL. I have had experience in education and IT infrastructure support. My interests include reading, cycling, basketball and watching sport. I enjoy spending time with my family and I have two amazing children, who are now young adults. I look forward to joining a development team to utilize and improve my coding skills.

Technical Skills

HTML

CSS

BootStrap

JavaScript

Node.js

Express.js

SQL

Sequelize

MongoDB

Graphql

React.js

Teaching Experience

As a teacher on contract I have taught ICT and Digital technologies at the following schools:

- Melville Senior High School Years 7,8,9 2020
- Mount Lawley Senior High School Years 7,8,9 2019
- Perth College Years 7.8,9,10 2018

ICT Industry Experience

I was a systems engineer with KineticIT for 2003 to 2016, working on the following client sites

- Inpex, 2013 -2016
- Building Management and Works, WA Govt, 2011 2013
- WA Police, 2007 2011
- Education Department, 2003 2007

Projects

Menu Planner: An application that allows users to record meal plans for the future and now by being able to review meals from the past.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, node.js, express, MongoDB, Graphql, React

Repository link: https://github.com/scottyv6/meal_planner
Web link: https://secure-garden-16153.herokuapp.com/

Book Inventory: A collaborative application that stores books and allows users to add their own reviews. If a book the user is looking for does not show up they are able to upload any book of their choice and then add their review from there.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, handlebars, node.js, express

Repository link: https://github.com/cal750/Book-Inventory

Web link: https://book-inventoryyy.herokuapp.com/

SongStar: A website where the user can search for songs and the search bar will provide the searched song from multiple different sites. The user will input key words and through the use of the Vimeo and YouTube APIs the website will respond with the most closely related matches.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma, Vimeo API, YouTube API

Repository link: https://github.com/scottyv6/SongStar Github pages link: https://scottyv6.github.io/SongStar

Work Day Scheduler: A web app to schedule and store appointment for the work day

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Boostrap

Repository link: https://github.com/scottyv6/SLV_Scheduler Github pages link: https://scottyv6.github.io/SLV_Scheduler/

Weather Dashboard: The Weather Dashboard app displays the weather for cities around the world and save previous searches as clickable buttons.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Open Weather Map API

Repository link: https://github.com/scottyv6/SLV_WeatherDash **Github pages link:** https://scottyv6.github.io/SLV_WeatherDash/

Qualifications

- Certificate, Full Stack Web Development University of Western Australia, completed Nov 2021
- Graduate Diploma in Education (ICT major; Mathematics minor) University of Western Australia, completed Nov 2017
- Bachelor of Science (Computer Science), Curtin University, 1996
- VMware Certificate Associate Data Center Virtualization, 2015
- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP) Installing and Configuring Windows Server, 2012
- Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE) (NT4)

Interests / Community Involvement

- Coach, City Beach Basketball Club (Miniball through to Under 18s boys' basketball team) 2011 - 2021
- Coach, Rosalie Primary School Boys Basketball Team, 2014
- Parent Volunteer, Rosalie Primary School Year 3 6 Camps (2009, 2010, 2012, 2015)